### Ed Summers

ehs@pobox.com / @edsu / 240-478-7086 304 Brewster Court, Silver Spring, MD 20901

I am a software developer with two decades of experience working at the intersection of libraries, archives and the World Wide Web. I study and work with the web as a sociotechnical system, with a particular eye to its evolving architecture and practices of curation and preservation.

# Experience

## Lead Software Developer

Maryland Institute for Technology in the Humanities August 2014 - Present

- Social media data collection, analysis and preservation
- Digital humanities research and development
- Web and cloud based infrastructure development and sustainability

### Information Technology Specialist

Library of Congress  $\,$ 

March 2006 - August 2014

- Digital preservation and repository software design and development
- Lead Software Developer on the National Digital Newspaper Project
- Social Media Archiving (Twitter)
- Design and implementation of the Library of Congress Linked Data Service
- Standards work in the World Wide Web Consortium: SKOS, RDFa, eGov

#### Senior Software Engineer

Follett Corporation

May 2002 - March 2006

- Design and construction of a distributed knowledge management applica-
- Requirements gathering and project planning
- Web Service design and implementation
- Metadata harvesting and analysis

### Education

#### PhD Information Studies

University of Maryland

2015 - Present

I am currently studying the activity of Web archiving, and Web archives as artifacts, through the lens of repair and sustainability studies.

# M.S. Library Science

Rutgers University 1995 - 1996

My studies focused on the use of the emerging Web to deploy reference and cataloging services.

# B.A. English

Rutgers University 1987 - 1991

In my senior seminars I focused on the study of the African American experience through the works of James Baldwin. I minored in Computer Science, and began my studies in the Engineering program.

References available upon request.